#### PERSONAL INFORMATION



#### David Barbosa Maia

- Rua Michel Giacometti N21 2D 2835-138 Baixa da Banheira
- **=** +351 913 387 023
- david.barbosa.maia@gmail.com
- 🗩 skype david.barbosa.maia

Sex Male | Date of birth 11/10/1989 | Nationality Portuguese

"There is nothing noble in being superior to your fellow man; true nobility is being superior to your former self." Ernest Hemingway

# SUMMARY

I love learning and programing using nothing but the command line, tmux, vim and a bunch of plugins. I am passionate about the craft of software development.

Apart from that I also love going to the gym, jumping rope, listening to classical music and playing piano. I am also a classically trained pianist and have been playing the piano since I was 16 years old.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Unbabel

#### October 2019 - Present

### Senior Software Engineer (Translation as a Service scale up)

Unbabel is a scale up SaaS company that handles translations in a global scale.

I am working for the community team enhancing and enriching the editors experience.

Front-end: Vue, Vuex, Vue Router,

**Back-end**: Python 2/3, Django, Flask, Mongodb **Dev Ops:** GitLab Pipelines, kubernetes, AWS, Docker

#### Mash

### January 2019 - October 2019

### Senior Software Engineer (FinTech scale up)

Mash is a scale up fintech company based in Finland. I worked on the Portuguese office in partnership with Inscale.

I mainly did front end development with a little bit of devops (mostly simple terraform scripts and playing around in azure).

I also did a presentation on how docker works under the hood (namespaces et al.)

**Front-end**: React (with hooks), Redux (with hooks, Styled Components, Recompose, Rebass, Styled Components, Recompose,

Back-end: .net 4.5, .net 4.5 MVC, .net core,

Dev Ops: Azure, Azure Pipelines, Terraform, Kubernetes, Docker

### **BitSight**

# January 2018 - Present

### Software Engineer (Security Ratings SaaS scale up)

Bitsight is a venture backed start-up company leader of the security ratings service.

I am a full stack software engineer currently working on the customer facing ratings portal.

**Front-end**: HTML5/CSS3 (SCSS). JS, ES6, React, Redux (w/ sagas), Babel, Webpack, npm/yarn, istanbul/mocha/chai/enzyme, jquery, lodash

Back-end: python 2.7, Django, Django rest-framework

Dev Ops: Jenkins, Chef, Kubernetes, Docker

- Thriving and fast paced engineering oriented environment with agile methodologies
- Maintenance and development of new features to customer facing portal

### everis centers

#### February 2017 - Present

### Software Engineer (Automotive Industry)

Partnership project with nTTData for BMW

**Technologies**: Java 7, Java EE 6, JAXB, JAX-RS, JAX-WS, EJB, MQ, Swing, JavaFX, Junit, Oracle SQL, Jenkins, Sonar, JIRA, SVN

 Maintenance and development for a complex Swing fat client app called Sales Assistant 3 that communicates with a Java EE application server. Integration with multiple interfaces (Web Services, message queues, etc.) to other BMW mission critical systems.

• Scrum daily meetings, continuous integration (Jenkins), Sonar, JIRA, SVN, etc.

#### everis

#### January 2016 - Present

### Full Stack Engineer (Public Sector)

Instituto de Gestão Financeira e Equipamentos da Justiça

Front-end: JQuery, Bootstrap

Back-end: .Net Framework 4.5 (Web Forms & MVC), EF, iTextSharp, WPF, WCF

- Full stack developer for a critical web application for the ministry of justice
- Maintenance and new developments of an existing .Net Web Forms application
- Development of a new web application (frontend & backend) from scratch using .Net MVC with Entity Framework (database first)

# September 2013 – January 2016

### Identity and Access Management Consultant (Banking)

)16 Caixa Geral de Depósitos

**Technologies**: CA Identity Minder, Serena Dimensions & Business Manager, Cucumber, TestNG, MS SQL, LDAP, Perl

- Java developer for an IAM project for a bank
- Developed a complex task with CA services to significantly speed up user creation
- Designed and implemented an automatic testing suite using Selenium
- Extensive contact with the client's application lifecycle management methodologies and software
- · Important role on a complex IAM software upgrade with major architectural changes

### May 2013 – August 2013

### Identity and Access Management Junior Consultant (Insurance)

Axa MedLA

Technologies: CA Identity Minder, CA Site Minder, Java, axis2, WSDL, XML, LDAP, JDBC

- Java Developer for an IAM regional project for an insurance company
- Direct contact and decision making influence with the client party of the project without direct supervision
- · Integrated new applications using web services

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

September 2010 – October 2012

Master Degree in Information Systems and Computer

Engineering

Instituto Superior Técnico

September 2007 - August 2010

Degree in Engineering Sciences – Information Systems and Computer Engineering

Instituto Superior Técnico

September 2006 – August 2012

# Musical Pratical Piano Forte Level 8 (out of 8)

Conservatório Regional de Setúbal

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

### Mother tongue(s)

### Portuguese

# Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
First Certificate in English, Cambridge ESOL				

# English

Skills

Frontend: HTML5/CSS3, JS, jQuery, React et al, Vue et al, Jest et al, Mocha et al.

Backend: .Net et al, Java et al, Python et al

**DB**:MS SQL Server, My SQL, Oracle DB, Mongo DB **DevOps**: AWS, Azure Pipeline, Gitlab Pipelines, Jenkins

Driving licence

В